Vlad Voloshyn

vladvoloshyn12@gmail.com, (093)-003-08-90

Summary

Infrastructure Engineer with passion to improve skills and learn smth new. About 5 years of evolving cloud/on-premise infrastructure and automating development workflow. Open source fan and great team player. Have worked for startups as well as top 100 fortune company. Not afraid of taking responsibility and prove value, have lead experience.

Education

NTUU KPI, IASA faculty – Master's degree, Computer Science

Experience

[05.2019–now] Infrastructure Engineer, PartsTech

- MariaDB, MongoDB schema and query optimizations, configuration tuning, setting up clustered ProxySQL for MariaDB Galera
- Migrating Elasticsearch to 6/7 releases, updating mappings, synonyms optimization, implementing custom routing
- Terraform, Ansible for managing multi-az AWS infrastructure
- Kubernetes, kops, helm/helmfile, kiam, Traefik ingress
- Distributed tracing implementation via Jaeger
- RabbitMQ cluster automatic bootstrap configuration
- Graylog maintenance and upgrading, changing to EFK stack
- Prometheus EC2 auto-discovery setup, AWS monitoring enhancements

[06.2018–07.2019] Infrastructure Engineer, LUN | Flatfy

- Multi-Cloud environment distributed in Hetzner, AWS and GCP
- Microservices within HashiCorp stack (Consul, Nomad, Vault, Packer, Terraform)
- Immutable infrastructure in stateless/stateful services
- Logs/metrics via ELK+Filebeat, statsd, Sentry, Prometheus + Trickster + Grafana
- Managing dbs (Elasticsearch, Percona, Postgres, Redis)

- Data migration to PXC multi-master cluster with ProxySQL in front
- Tuning Elasticsearch search and index performance
- SaltStack, queueing with RabbitMQ, Docker, Jenkins
- Weave overlay network, OpenVPN/Pritunl, Fabio, Nginx, keepalived
- Automated managing of DNS zones and records via OctoDNS
- Python, Flask, Celery, Alembic SQLAlchemy

[03.2017–05.2018] DevOps Engineer, SoftServe

- Monitoring and maintenance 24/7 real-time highload system, improving to make it auto scalable and cost-effective. Being on-call and taking part in developing new platform. Expertise in mentoring junior engineers.
- Manage services that require long periods of draining
- Use smp affinity to pin device interrupts to specific core in Ubuntu
- Server configuration for IOS/Android push notifications
- AWS, Chef, Terraform, Capistrano, Datadog, New Relic, ElasticSearch, Redis, MySQL, Bamboo+Bitbucket Pipelines, Packer, Vagrant, Rundeck, Splunk, JFrog Artifactory, PagerDuty
- Python (writing Lambda functions), Ruby, Bash, Golang
- Automatic backup validation and DR actions
- Work on monitoring enhancement

[11.2014–05.2018] System/Network Administrator, NTUU "KPI"

- Network with 100+ PC and 30+ *nix type bare-metal servers support and maintenance
- Provisioning and configuring Web servers, proxies (Apache, Nginx, Squid)
- Xen, databases, LDAP, mail, monitoring with Nagios/Cacti
- dhcpd, ipfw, mpd5, named, Zoneminder, Nextcloud
- Networking, Cisco switch/AP configuration, VPN, DNS servers, IP-cameras
- FreeBSD/Linux kernel building and tuning
- Managing team of System Administrators

Miscellaneous

English level - B2 (Upper-Intermediate)

Github profile - https://github.com/volym3ad

Regularly taking part in hackathons, conferences, workshops, writing stories on Medium (https://medium.com/@vvol), dou devops digest co-author.